Hope Starts Here
----------------

You Can Double Your Impact! Every contribution made by December 31 will be MATCHED up to $75,000! Your generosity brings hope and safety to victims and survivors, creating lasting change for them and their families.

* [Skip to navigation \[n\]](#nav "Skip to navigation")
* [Skip to content \[c\]](#content "Skip to content")
* [Skip to footer \[f\]](#footer "Skip to footer")

---------

    * [National Conference on  
        Domestic Violence](https://www.thehotline.org/national-conference-on-domestic-violence/)

Search  _Search_ [_Close_](#)

### Leave this site safely

**You can quickly leave this website by clicking the “X” in the top right or by pressing the Escape key twice.**

To browse this site safely, be sure to regularly clear your browser history.

Security Alert
--------------

Internet usage can be monitored and is impossible to erase completely. If you’re concerned your internet usage might be monitored, call us at 800.799.SAFE (7233). **[Learn more about digital security](https://www.thehotline.org/plan-for-safety/internet-safety/)** and remember to clear your browser history after visiting this website.

**Click the red “X” in the upper-right corner or “Escape” button on your keyboard twice at any time to leave TheHotline.org immediately.**

Privacy Policy
==============

**The National Domestic Violence Hotline – Digital Services** is the organization which provides all advocacy services on [www.thehotline.org](https://www.thehotline.org/) and through 24-hour telephone services at 1-800-799-7233.

Anonymous Digital Service is defined as a one-time confidential contact between a user and advocate in which no identifying information is verified.

**The Hotline Provides Digital Services**

Engaging in our digital services constitutes an agreement and understanding of privacy policy. Digital services are defined as web based chat, YouTube, Twitter, Facebook, Instagram, Flickr, The Hotline blog or any Hotline website or web-based comment section. If at any time, a digital service user feels that their safety or privacy may be compromised due their use of these services, the interaction can be escalated to phone-based services.

**Opt-Out Policy**

The Hotline gives users options for non-digital services when necessary and practical. Such choices include opting not to engage in digital services and opting not to provide identifiable information during interactions with advocates. Users concerned for their physical safety and well-being are encouraged to contact The Hotline at 1-800-799-7233.

**Confidential and Anonymous Chat**

Our live chat services are provided by Caspio as a service (SaaS) provider. Chat users are asked to enter their name and other personal information to facilitate service with an operator. IP addresses are also required to facilitate a connection. Information collected from a user on a voluntary basis can include:

* Organization name
* Gender
* Age
* City
* State
* Zip
* How user-heard about the service

The National Domestic Violence Hotline collects limited demographic and geo-locational information in order to provide services. The National Domestic Violence Hotline defines anonymous communication as a onetime individual contact where digital services are provided between a chatter and advocate in which no information is collected that can connect the user to the individual service interaction. Dialogue transcripts of chats are purged regularly. Any information that is temporarily maintained is core to our evaluation of services provided to persons contacting the National Domestic Violence Hotline. Identifying information is in no way cross-verified. A chat user’s information, including any personally identifiable information, will only be shared with persons implicitly linked to The Hotline’s operations. We do not sell, trade or rent personal information that chat users provide. All advocates, including volunteers, are required to sign a client confidentiality policy. After any chat or email session, persons contacting The Hotline may be asked to fill out an exit survey in order to provide valuable feedback about our service. Providing information in an exit survey is completely voluntary. Surveys may ask for contact information (e.g., email address) and for demographic information (e.g., zip code, age or income level).

**Text/SMS Messaging Services**

The Hotline offers services through a text message short code in which all inbound phone-numbers are scrambled. These services include:

* Text-for-help services: The same privacy standards applied to our chat services apply to our text-for-help platform. Any statement of charges or billing will appear as a text message sent to Waterfall, based in Austin, and is in no way connected to The Hotline. Users may be asked to provide voluntary feedback to survey questions.
* Opt-in newsletter/updates: Users can opt-in to receive regular messages providing updates relevant issue-related content. Users can opt-out any time. While numbers may be  scrambled, but users may provide voluntary feedback to survey questions.
* One-time information messages: These are one-time messages are sent to a user to inform the user of specific issue content. The user has the option to learn more on follow-up page. No further communication will occur unless prompted by the user. The Hotline will not provide crisis services in this type of interaction.

Users can opt-out of services by texting ‘STOP’ to our shortcode any time. Users can get help by texting ‘HELP’ to our shortcode any time. Message and data rates may apply. Users will be charged standard text messaging rates relative to their provider’s plans. Carriers are not liable for the delayed or undelivered messages. Message frequency may vary. Users should be aware and mindful that text messages sent using modern smart phones are saved indefinitely and could compromise their safety. Users concerned for their physical safety and well-being are encouraged to contact The Hotline at 1-800-799-7233.

**Software as a Service and Application Service Providers (3rd party)**

The Hotline will undertake an annual review of any third party privacy policies affecting Hotline services. The Hotline is not responsible for changes or updates made in the interim.

Cookies The Hotline may use cookies to enhance your experience while using our site. Cookies are pieces of information that some websites use to transfer to the user’s computer and are used for record-keeping purposes. Use of cookies makes web navigation easier by performing certain functions such as saving your passwords, your personal preferences and to make sure you don’t see the same advertisement repeatedly. Many consider the use of cookies to be an industry standard. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. Your browser is probably set to accept cookies. However, if you would prefer not to receive cookies, you can alter the configuration of your browser to refuse cookies. If you choose to have your browser refuse cookies, it is possible that some areas of our site will not function properly when you view them.

**Legal Disclosure**

We may access and/or disclose personally identifiable information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or (b) comply with legal process served on us.

**Mandatory Reporting**

The Hotline’s advocates are considered mandatory reporters by law. Users will be made aware that in situations regarding the welfare of a minor, any locating information disclosed will be reported to child protective services as required.

**Technical Information**

Our web servers automatically collect non-personal information such as the domain name of the Internet access provider, the Internet protocol address used to connect the computer to the Internet, the average time spent on our website, pages viewed, information searched for, access times and other relevant statistics.

**Other Websites**

Our site and services offer links to other websites. Please note that when you click on one of these links, you are entering another website for which The Hotline has no responsibility. We encourage you to read the privacy statements on all such sites as their policies may differ from ours.

**Donations**

When you make a donation on The Hotline’s website by clicking the Donate link in the menu, we must share some of your personally identifiable information with third parties in order to process the transaction. For example, we must share your credit card number with our credit card processor BBMS (Blackbaud Merchant Services) who utilizes the Raiser’s Edge software in order to process your payment. These third parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services. We do not share any of your personally identifiable information with unrelated third parties for their own marketing purposes without your consent.

**Notification of Policy Changes**

We reserve the right to change, modify or add to our privacy policy to protect the ethical standards provided or to meet the changing demands of digital advocacy. Notification of any changes to The Hotline’s privacy policy will be posted to the homepage (at [thehotline.org](https://www.thehotline.org/)) or other appropriate location so as to adequately inform digital service users of these revisions. We encourage you to please review it frequently.

**Contacting the Website**

If you have any questions about this privacy policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, please contact:

**National Domestic Violence Hotline  
****P.O. Box 90249, Austin, TX 78709  

#### Contact

National Domestic Violence Hotline  
PO Box 90249  
Austin, Texas 78709  
Administrative Line: 737-225-3150

#### Follow

The Hotline®  
National Domestic Violence Hotline

This project was supported by Grant Number 90EV0459 from the Administration on Children, Youth and Families, Family and Youth Services Bureau, U.S. Department of Health and Human Services. The opinions, findings, conclusions and recommendations expressed in this publication are those of the author(s) and do not necessarily reflect the views of the Administration on Children, Youth and Families, Family and Youth Services Bureau, U.S. Department of Health and Human Services.

Exempted from federal income tax under the provisions of Section 501(c) (3) of the Internal Revenue Code.

This Web site is funded through Grant 2020-V3-GX-0135 from the Office for Victims of Crime, Office of Justice Programs, U.S. Department of Justice. Neither the U.S. Department of Justice nor any of its components operate, control, are responsible for, or necessarily endorse, this Web site (including, without limitation, its content, technical infrastructure, and policies, and any services or tools provided.

* [Text "START" to 88788
    
    _Visit our page for Privacy Policy. Msg & Data Rates May Apply. Text STOP to opt out._](sms:88788?&body=START)
